{"content": "Just a friendly reminder that phishing scams which spoof the boss and request W-2 tax data on employees are intensifying as tax time nears. The latest victim shows that even cybersecurity experts can fall prey to these increasingly sophisticated attacks. On Thursday, March 16, the CEO of Defense Point Security, LLC — a Virginia company that bills itself as “the choice provider of cyber security services to the federal government” — told all employees that their W-2 tax data was handed directly to fraudsters after someone inside the company got caught in a phisher’s net. Alexandria, Va.-based Defense Point Security (recently acquired by management consulting giant Accenture) informed current and former employees this week via email that all of the data from their annual W-2 tax forms — including name, Social Security Number, address, compensation, tax withholding amounts — were snared by a targeted spear phishing email. “I want to alert you that a Defense Point Security (DPS) team member was the victim of a targeted spear phishing email that resulted in the external release of IRS W-2 Forms for individuals who DPS employed in 2016,” Defense Point CEO George McKenzie wrote in the email alert to employees. “Unfortunately, your W-2 was among those released outside of DPS.” W-2 scams start with spear phishing emails usually directed at finance and HR personnel. The scam emails will spoof a request from the organization’s CEO (or someone similarly high up in the organization) and request all employee W-2 forms. Defense Point did not return calls or emails seeking comment. An Accenture spokesperson issued the following brief statement:  “Data protection and our employees are top priorities. Our leadership and security team are providing support to all impacted employees.” Fraudsters who perpetrate tax refund fraud prize W-2 information because it contains virtually all of the data one would need to fraudulently file someone’s taxes and request a large refund in their name. Scammers in tax years past also have massively phished online payroll management account credentials used by corporate HR professionals. This year, they are going after people who run tax preparation firms, and W-2’s are now being openly sold in underground cybercrime stores. Tax refund fraud affects hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of U.S. citizens annually. Victims usually first learn of the crime after having their returns rejected because scammers beat them to it. Even those who are not required to file a return can be victims of refund fraud, as can those who are not actually due a refund from the IRS.", "sourcefile": "10064.txt", "cyberevent": {"hopper": [{"index": 0, "relation": "Same", "events": [{"index": "E3", "type": "Attack", "realis": "Actual", "nugget": {"startOffset": 479, "index": "T5", "endOffset": 489, "text": "was handed"}, "argument": [{"index": "T6", "text": "their W-2 tax data", "endOffset": 478, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 460, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T7", "text": "all employees", "endOffset": 454, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 441, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T8", "text": "fraudsters", "endOffset": 512, "role": {"type": "Attacker"}, "startOffset": 502, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Databreach"}, {"index": "E5", "type": "Attack", "realis": "Actual", "nugget": {"startOffset": 885, "index": "T15", "endOffset": 896, "text": "were snared"}, "argument": [{"index": "T21", "text": "tax withholding amounts", "endOffset": 882, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 859, "type": "Data"}, {"index": "T20", "text": "compensation", "endOffset": 857, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 845, "type": "Data"}, {"index": "T19", "text": "address", "endOffset": 843, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 836, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T18", "text": "Social Security Number", "endOffset": 834, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 812, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T17", "text": "name", "endOffset": 810, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 806, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T14", "text": "annual W-2 tax forms", "endOffset": 793, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 773, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T13", "text": "data", "endOffset": 761, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 757, "type": "Data"}, {"index": "T16", "text": "spear phishing email", "endOffset": 931, "role": {"type": "Tool"}, "startOffset": 911, "type": "File"}, {"index": "T44", "text": "employees", "endOffset": 720, "role": {"type": "Attacker"}, "startOffset": 711, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Databreach"}, {"index": "E6", "type": "Attack", "realis": "Actual", "nugget": {"startOffset": 1069, "index": "T24", "endOffset": 1089, "text": "the external release"}, "argument": [{"index": "T22", "text": "team member", "endOffset": 1001, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 990, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T23", "text": "spear phishing email", "endOffset": 1051, "role": {"type": "Tool"}, "startOffset": 1031, "type": "File"}, {"index": "T25", "text": "IRS W-2 Forms", "endOffset": 1106, "role": {"type": "Compromised-Data"}, "startOffset": 1093, "type": "PII"}, {"index": "T26", "text": "individuals", "endOffset": 1122, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 1111, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T27", "text": "2016", "endOffset": 1147, "role": {"type": "Time"}, "startOffset": 1143, "type": "Time"}, {"index": "T42", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q1061846"}, "endOffset": 1130, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "text": "DPS", "startOffset": 1127, "type": "Organization"}, {"index": "T45", "text": "Defense Point Security (DPS)", "endOffset": 989, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 961, "type": "Organization"}], "subtype": "Databreach"}]}, {"index": 1, "relation": "Same", "events": [{"index": "E2", "type": "Attack", "realis": "General", "nugget": {"startOffset": 51, "index": "T2", "endOffset": 56, "text": "spoof"}, "argument": [{"index": "T3", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q1225"}, "endOffset": 65, "role": {"type": "Trusted-Entity"}, "text": "the boss", "startOffset": 57, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T4", "text": "request W-2 tax data", "endOffset": 90, "role": {"type": "Purpose", "subtype": "Gathering data", "confidence": 0.8421726524829865}, "startOffset": 70, "type": "Purpose"}, {"index": "T43", "text": "employees", "endOffset": 103, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 94, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Phishing"}, {"nugget": {"startOffset": 30, "index": "T1", "endOffset": 44, "text": "phishing scams"}, "index": "E1", "type": "Attack", "subtype": "Phishing", "realis": "General"}]}, {"index": 2, "events": [{"index": "E8", "type": "Attack", "realis": "General", "nugget": {"startOffset": 1395, "index": "T32", "endOffset": 1405, "text": "will spoof"}, "argument": [{"index": "T33", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q484876"}, "endOffset": 1443, "role": {"type": "Trusted-Entity"}, "text": "CEO", "startOffset": 1440, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T34", "text": "The scam emails", "endOffset": 1394, "role": {"type": "Tool"}, "startOffset": 1379, "type": "File"}, {"index": "T35", "text": "someone", "endOffset": 1455, "role": {"type": "Trusted-Entity"}, "startOffset": 1448, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T36", "text": "request all employee W-2 forms", "endOffset": 1529, "role": {"type": "Purpose", "subtype": "Gathering data", "confidence": 0.8253774642944336}, "startOffset": 1499, "type": "Purpose"}, {"index": "T40", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q1071976"}, "endOffset": 1493, "role": {"type": "Trusted-Entity"}, "text": "the organization", "startOffset": 1477, "type": "Organization"}, {"index": "T41", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q15911314"}, "endOffset": 1437, "role": {"type": "Trusted-Entity"}, "text": "organization", "startOffset": 1425, "type": "Organization"}], "subtype": "Phishing"}]}, {"index": 3, "events": [{"index": "E9", "type": "Attack", "realis": "Actual", "nugget": {"startOffset": 2048, "index": "T37", "endOffset": 2055, "text": "phished"}, "argument": [{"index": "T39", "text": "HR professionals", "endOffset": 2136, "role": {"type": "Attacker"}, "startOffset": 2120, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T38", "text": "Scammers", "endOffset": 2009, "role": {"type": "Attacker"}, "startOffset": 2001, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Phishing"}]}, {"index": 4, "events": [{"index": "E7", "type": "Attack", "realis": "General", "nugget": {"startOffset": 1290, "index": "T28", "endOffset": 1299, "text": "W-2 scams"}, "argument": [{"index": "T30", "external_reference": {"wikidataid": "Q5449524"}, "endOffset": 1360, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "text": "finance", "startOffset": 1353, "type": "Organization"}, {"index": "T29", "text": "spear phishing emails", "endOffset": 1332, "role": {"type": "Tool"}, "startOffset": 1311, "type": "File"}, {"index": "T31", "text": "HR personnel", "endOffset": 1377, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 1365, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Phishing"}]}, {"index": 5, "events": [{"index": "E4", "type": "Attack", "realis": "Actual", "nugget": {"startOffset": 546, "index": "T11", "endOffset": 556, "text": "got caught"}, "argument": [{"index": "T10", "text": "the company", "endOffset": 545, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 534, "type": "Organization"}, {"index": "T9", "text": "someone", "endOffset": 526, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 519, "type": "Person"}, {"index": "T12", "text": "phisher", "endOffset": 569, "role": {"type": "Victim"}, "startOffset": 562, "type": "Person"}], "subtype": "Phishing"}]}]}, "info": {"title": "Govt. Cybersecurity Contractor Hit in W-2 Phishing Scam", "date": "2017_03_17", "type": "text", "link": "https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/03/govt-cybersecurity-contractor-hit-in-w-2-phishing-scam/"}}